<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[A Music Blog...]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[A Music Blog...]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/jupiter-variation/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 18:47:50 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/jupiter-variation/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 18:47:49 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This blog has moved…]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>This blog has moved…</h1><p>…please find us in our new address….

</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/jupiter-variation/this-blog-has-moved/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">cc5c91fa-ccdc-40f4-a12a-b5f67003afd1</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 18:47:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Swans & Anna von Hausswolff - Kaserne Basel *Musik*, 28 October 2016]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Swans & Anna von Hausswolff - Kaserne Basel *Musik*, 28 October 2016</h1><p>After I arrived in Kaserne I headed straight to the bar in order to buy myself a beer. On the bench, I immediately noticed the usual box with the earplugs and an ironic smile appeared on my face (for those not familiar, in Switzerland the volume of club and live concert music is regulated by law to 99 db and whenever needed - like in Heavy Metal concerts or gigs like Swans - the concert promoter is obliged to supply free earplugs to the audience). “I think you will need them tonight”, the barman said to me and he continued: “I watched their soundcheck and they are loud…really, really loud”. For a moment I wanted to start telling him stories about the infamous Swans performances of the 80’s, where the music volume was reaching to 140 db and usually had to be stopped after intervention from the Police but I decided that I am too bored to start such a discussion in German, I just smiled at him, took a pair of fancy, fluorescent ones from the box and moved in front of the stage.</p><img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/f37f97ac-5276-45ef-91d0-eb0a77b4bb12.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/jupiter-variation/swans-and-anna-von-hausswolff-kaserne-basel-musik-28-octo/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ab427281-c9ac-45f9-a6c5-1fe5bdae10da</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 19:20:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I like my music, just like my salad…Greek (Summer-Autumn 2016 Version)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>I like my music, just like my salad…Greek (Summer-Autumn 2016 Version)</h1><p>Greek scene is alive and kicking so I have decided to present some of the best releases that came into my hands during this summer-autumn. Enjoy and support your local scene, wherever you are…</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/961b05a971588329bab096ab4909a49989678c97.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/jupiter-variation/i-like-my-music-just-like-my-saladgreek-summer-autumn-201/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">745b6291-97e8-4120-b727-5544a72a2b92</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 06:50:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PJ Harvey - Zurich Hallenstadion, 25 October 2016]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>PJ Harvey - Zurich Hallenstadion, 25 October 2016</h1><p>Choosing a weekday evening (and especially a Tuesday) is not a success factor when it comes to concert ticket sales. These were my first thoughts at the moment I disembarked from the tram in front of an almost empty entrance of Zurich’s Hallenstadion. After double checking my ticket (in order to ensure that I am in the correct venue) I entered the stadium and proceeded to the concert hall. 45 minutes before the official concert start and what I was seeing was heartbreaking. Less than 200 people in a venue that in its full capacity can accommodate 13.000 attendants. For tonights concert, the scene had been setup in the middle of the field creating a venue for 2.000 - 3.000 but until that moment the omens where still not good. I went to my seat and after a couple of minutes a very polite lady from the crew, informed me (in Swiss German) that If I want I can move to the arena as there would be enough capacity this night (for the ones who are not familiar with the Swiss respect and adherence to the rules, normally such a change is strictly forbidden due to safety reasons). With a very convincing and almost apologetic face she also explained that she understands that I have paid more for a seat so If I wish I could remain in the nearly empty side of the seated places. The omens for tonight were becoming more and more worse but I decided not to let this affect my mood so I grabbed a beer and moved down to the arena (where by that time, 30 min before the concert start, you could easily set up a small football match).</p><img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ed1b42e7-0199-4bf1-8f11-f1a82e421f68.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/jupiter-variation/pj-harvey-zurich-hallenstadion-25-october-2016/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ea9033e0-1fee-417b-a38a-092d0ab690f8</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 08:24:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[מזמור - Yodh (2016)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>מזמור - Yodh (2016)</h1><p>One question that constantly revolves around my head is what can really help a musician standout and survive in today’s landscape of over-information, short attention span (audience-wise) and oversupply of musical output. There are hundreds of new albums coming out each month, thousands (literally) of blogs and music portals out there and me personally, both as a fan and a collector, really struggle to absorb all the amount of available music and keep my collection decently up to date. In this matter, Internet has been both a blessing and a curse. Nowadays, most of the music is at your disposal with a mouse-click but on the other hand this “over convenience” has removed the personal part from the music listening process. You click, you listen for some minutes and if the album does not keep your attention you abort and send the files to the computer trashcan. On the other hand, in the cases you physically purchase an album, by the time it arrives at your hands you have most probably already listened to it a couple of times and you only file it in your shelves for archiving or completist reasons (out of where most probably it will very rarely come out again since you can listen it in Spotify or in your smartphone). What I really miss are the times when I was waiting for Saturday morning to come, in order to embark for my trip towards the city centre, visit all the record stores one by one holding the list I was thoroughly compiling the previous weeks, make my fingers dirty and sore from searching and finally return home, isolate in my room and spend the rest of the weekend listening to my newly purchased records and noting down the songs which would be later included in my mix-tapes.</p><img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/34714afc-e66c-40f6-9001-904425ab7111.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/jupiter-variation/-yodh-2016/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">8f6c3555-f515-4531-b4e9-cad42ec4fd3a</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 16:30:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Music in 7 inches, part 1]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Music in 7 inches, part 1</h1><h2>Hissing - Cairn/Husk (2016)</h2><p>Hissing come from Seattle and they play Grim, Blackened Death Metal with absolutely no sign of melody or groove. The 7 inch comes out from Southern Lord in a wonderful clear vinyl and is worthy every dime of the 6,66 USD that it costs. Hissing’s only other release is a self titled 4-track cassette E.P.</p><img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/9684ffa1-88c4-4476-a2f4-8945491c7282.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/jupiter-variation/music-in-7-inches-part-1/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d7c3d2e8-299c-4acc-b966-e67fca358323</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 13:36:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Red Hot Chili Peppers - Zurich Hallenstadion, 5 October 2016]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Red Hot Chili Peppers - Zurich Hallenstadion, 5 October 2016</h1><p>Halfway through the concert I overheard a girl who was standing next to me saying to her boyfriend that this is a strange gig for her. Well for sure it was a strange gig, especially for the ones who got to know RHCP during the Californication era or the ones who mention bands like RHCP when they claim to their friends that they listen to Alternative Rock (sic). Without wanting to sound like an elitist (or at least too much), I felt that this concert was for the ones who really love RHCP for being the pioneers who pushed the envelope with albums like Mother’s Milk or for being the geniuses who delivered albums intelligent in their simplicity like Blood Sugar Sex Magic…this is what I was thinking while seeing the puzzled faces of many of the spectators during songs like Nobody Weird Like Me (who was delivered with incredible ferocity) or the questioning silence during the improvisational jams that were played between nearly each song…this puzzlement was becoming much more apparent every time RHCP were returning to their radio standards…at these moments the audience was suddenly reacting like a volcano erupting…I have to say that RHCP manipulated the audience wisely…they left out many concert standards (Under the Bridge for example) and this made the audience anticipate and react like crazy each time (finally) a hit-single was (flawlessly) played between each noisy, improvisational jam…well played trick, really well played…</p><img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/6196c282-df2c-4698-bfbc-f7cf7d67b269.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/jupiter-variation/red-hot-chili-peppers-zurich-hallenstadion-5-october-2016/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">197658a1-474c-4664-b122-16ad4aaf3f9b</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 21:07:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Various Artists - Decades of Destruction (Hammer 1986 - 2016)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Various Artists - Decades of Destruction (Hammer 1986 - 2016)</h1><p>To be honest, nowadays most of the magazine cover-mount CDs are pure shit (and the recent Kerrang tribute to Iron Maiden is a fine example of this) so to really be able to deliver an interesting result (which will eventually boost the sales in a slowly dying market) someone has to come up with something really unique, possibly by incorporating a few of the following things :</p><img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/ff801a24-1ec9-4115-8306-cf4dee9118b7.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/jupiter-variation/various-artists-decades-of-destruction-hammer-1986-2016/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9b21d436-ab30-4bd8-af8c-0a3313845a6b</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 20:27:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I Am the Morning - Lighthouse (2016)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>I Am the Morning - Lighthouse (2016)</h1><p>Lighthouse was awarded Album of the Year 2016 in the Progressive Music Awards, I Am the Morning record for Kscope, Mariusz Duda from Riverside performs a duet in the self-titled song and normally all these facts should be enough for someone to understand that I Am the Morning play Prog Rock. However, that would be much too restricting and diminishing for the music of the Russian duo (Marjana Semkina in vocals and Gleb Kolyadin in piano) who in their third studio album (plus 1 EP and 1 live album) deliver some of the most beautiful music I have ever heard.</p><img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/828b1022-e5e5-4b62-9644-291f9c59df81.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/jupiter-variation/i-am-the-morning-lighthouse-2016/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">db47c974-e641-4e06-a10f-88884400ccb8</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 20:26:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marriages - Salome (2015)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Marriages - Salome (2015)</h1><p>Truth is that this is a late discovery since Salome was released back in 2015 but nevertheless, better late than never. Marriages were formed by Emma Ruth Rundle and Greg Burns after Red Sparrows went on hiatus in 2012. With the addition of Dave Clifford in drums they released an E.P. (Kitsune 2012) and toured during 2013 with other Sargent House stars like Chelsea Wolfe, Russian Circles and Deafheaven. In 2014, Burns was replaced by Andrew Clinco and with their finalised line up, Marriages recorded and released Salome in 2015.</p><img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/cd561501-2e7c-41cb-b0b6-5434e0acdb50.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/jupiter-variation/marriages-salome-2015/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4030360a-4ef2-416b-bd39-a80b238f33d0</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 18:17:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>